He's in for the royal treatment.
Shrek the Third is a fantasy, adventure,
animation film directed by Chris Miller.
The King of Far Far Away has died and Shrek and
Fiona are to become King & Queen.
However, Shrek wants to return to his cozy swamp and live in peace and quiet, so when he finds out
there is another heir to the throne, they set off to bring him back to rule the kingdom.
Shrek (voice), played by Mike Myers.
Donkey (voice), played by Eddie Murphy.
Princess Fiona (voice), played by Cameron Diaz.
Puss in Boots (voice), played by Antonio Banderas.
Queen Lillian (voice), played by Julie Andrews.
King Harold (voice), played by John Cleese.
Shrek the Third (also known as Shrek 3) is a 2007 American animated fantasy
comedy film loosely based on the 1990 children's picture book Shrek!
by William Steig.
Directed by Chris Miller and co-directed by Raman Hui from
a screenplay by Jeffrey Price, Peter S.
Seaman, Miller, and producer Aron Warner, and a story conceived by Andrew Adamson, co-director of the previous two
installments, it is the sequel to Shrek 2 (2004) and the third installment in the Shrek film series.
The film features Mike Myers, Eddie Murphy, Cameron Diaz, Antonio Banderas, Rupert Everett, Julie Andrews, and John Cleese reprising their
voice roles from the previous films, along with new additions Justin Timberlake as Arthur Pendragon and Eric Idle as Merlin.
In the film, Prince Charming is plotting to overthrow Shrek and Fiona, who
have inherited the throne following King Harold's death.
Shrek has no interest in ruling the kingdom and attempts to convince Fiona's
underachieving 16-year-old cousin Artie to reign instead.
Shrek the Third premiered at the Mann Village Theatre, Westwood in Los Angeles on May 6, 2007, and
was theatrically released in the United States by Paramount Pictures on May 18, 2007.
Despite mixed reviews, the film was a commercial success, grossing $808.3 million worldwide on
a budget of $160 million, becoming the fourth-highest-grossing film of 2007.
It was nominated for Best Animated Film at the 61st British Academy Film Awards.
A sequel, Shrek Forever After, was released on May 21, 2010.
The film explores themes of ship, island, ambush, kingdom, boarding school.
The tone is lighthearted.